so remember on that one post that i did
about volleys you said you love to bali
let's work on your valley today okay
let's start off just going back and
forth you got a continental grip
yeah we go back and forth to each other
okay ready position you got to go like
this look this
yeah two hand is fine yeah two-handed is
fine
that's why we already remember that
first time we we played together
or it was the second time i think the
one hand is okay if you're completely
stretched out
but if it's close you do two hands it's
completely fine especially if you're
weak here
which most people are a little bit weak
in the beginning it'll strengthen as you
go along you can transition to
no no one hand here because look
the wrist bends backwards and you have
stability here
the wrist is bending here so you have
naturally a more stable
contact point
there we go
it's not bad but how about this see when
you wait on this side
the well no but you you're hitting a
four-hour then you're leaving the racket
here
so then if a backhand comes the path is
too long to go from here to here
come back you have to come back to the
middle all right go right in the middle
of the cord
good here we go okay
not bad somebody in the comment section
said your sunglasses are too dark
and are they too dark
they're from fishing yeah you see good
out of them right
oh yeah okay good
okay so you see one thing you're doing
now is you're kind of like getting a
little bit afraid of the ball you're
starting to back up you're starting to
back up
hold your ground don't allow your body
to back up it's not like on the baseline
where you have
time to back up and give yourself more
room to hit here you can't back up
there's not enough time
so you got to hold your ground you got
to be like a like very stable
like a tree okay very still and stable
like this
when you're violing now of course you
got to move to the ball and set it up
but when you're executing the value you
want to be as still as possible
good be still go down a little more down
anna down a little more look how i am
see how my upper body is down slightly
you see this and rack it up
rack it up body down
there you go
come again
move that ball in between the valleys
you gotta recover okay
so you hit a foreign valley you go right
back here quickly
good good
there it is good
okay come again
nice all right rack it up your racket is
dropping a little bit
racket head up there you go down
okay what happens is if you don't adjust
your body to a ball that's lower
naturally the racquet will go down like
this you see the right
adjust my body yeah so if you don't if
you just this
look at me now stay in the middle there
if i get a low ball and i don't bend
how can i get this low ball i got to
bring my racket down it's no good
because then you'll hit the ball up so
when the ball is lower you got to bend
so you want to maintain this angle of
the racket face you want the racket head
to be slightly above the handle
like this same on the back end okay so
that means is that when the ball is
lower you got to bring your body down
in order to maintain this angle of the
racket face
exactly doesn't necessarily have to be a
lunge what if the ball comes like right
at you
then just go like go like this you know
whatever whatever you need to do
in order to get down to a low ball
go again backhand and another one come
here don't turn too much the tendency
sometimes is to go like this and turn
stay a little bit more open good
good there it is don't be scared of the
ball come on
good good
now i'm going to go back to the baseline
and now the ball is going to have a lot
more pace
so don't be scared a lot of people get
scared when the ball comes at them
faster than that here move these two
please
you stay at the net and you volley back
to me i'm going to be at the baseline
you stay right here
good come back to me
good keep the racket head keep the
racquet head still
all you're doing is just freezing the
racket at contact you're freezing
good good
go again backhand good
nice one hand on the forehead one hand
good very nice
very nice volley very good okay now i'm
gonna give you a little more heat okay
i'm gonna rip the ball at you don't be
scared
nothing's going to happen i promise no
helm is required
but don't be scared i want you to lose
the fear of the ball
see that no need to be scared
okay it's not always going to be
forehand you got to be ready
good good
good wow anna
very good i want to teach you a new shot
today this one's called
swing bali swing wally swing volley
valley
it's evident oh bali
yeah i'm saying it's wrong too but uh
it's like basically a forehand
hit in the air so you hit a forehand
in the air and this is a shot like have
you ever played someone that gives you
like high balls
and it's kind of annoying because they
bounce high you have to back up
i usually do this with two hands what is
this
i didn't teach you this two-handed
overhead this is like
what i started doing don't do that
intuitive thing
i'm sorry okay well listen the intuitive
tennis intuitively
when you start playing tennis you're not
going to do it right you know you're
going to use the wrong grip on the serve
you're going to use the wrong
right channel no the channel is the
methodology is based on learning the
right fundamentals and then
once you learn the right fundamentals
with repetition certain things
on the strokes will happen intuitively
but when you first step on a court
you're not going to be intuitive you're
going to be doing everything wrong
serving with like a pancake and doing
all kinds of stuff so don't do this
i'm going to clean this couple times i'm
going to check that i'm going to check
that shot today okay
we're going to go over that but swing
valley basically is like when somebody
gives you a high ball
instead of letting it bounce you can
take it in the air like a forehand
so try it out stand right here behind
the service line usually this ball is
struck
anywhere between like the service line
and about
the middle between the uh service line
and the baseline
in this area you can do swing volleys
okay yeah it's like recognizable piece
of
shot so i would learn how to green it if
that's
applicable like is there any hints
yes of course that's a really good
question so that's what i call ball
recognition so that's where a lot of
people
get it wrong they don't have red ball
recognition but in this case because
it's so obvious
the recognition of this ball is quite
easy because you're going to see it's
being high
very high so you're going to be in the
baseline
or maybe you're going to be inside the
court a little bit so it's not something
that's going to be able to
you're going to be able to do close to
the net that then you might hit an
overhead or
or run back and run down a lot but if
you're in this area and the ball is
coming high
and you know it's going again you can
feel that it's going in instead of
letting it bounce and backing up you
take it in the air
but you'll recognize it quite easily
okay yeah because i usually
land and i'm staying but here's the way
people here's where people
get it wrong all the time they they can
recognize the ball and a lot of times
their
instinct would tell them oh don't don't
take this in the air let it bounce and
be safe
because it does require a little bit of
courage to do the shot so when you see
this ball you do have to decide
early to do a swing volley that makes
sense forehand
grip yes of course here we go
oh again okay so you do everything the
same as the forehand
watch you're gonna go like this and then
go like this
it's basically a forehand just waiting
yeah let me let me back up i want to
show you something here
here do a normal form do a forehand
do your normal forehand
do it again now do that same for you in
the air
do it in the air there you go
do it it's okay good again
good again nice
nice here we go no that's not
that's not a swing volley that's like a
hybrid between an overhead and a swing
valley this is this is something i don't
want you to do
okay i don't want you to do this i want
you to take a regular forehand swing now
the contact's going to be higher
it's going to be like i would say
between the
shoulder and your rib cage here now
sometimes it'll get a little bit above
the shoulders still okay
if it gets in your at your head level
it's going to be too high up here it's
going to be very uncomfortable
so you're going to take it around here
optimally right around the shoulder and
then you just go like that
well it's been out it's a risky shot
you know it's it's not necessarily a
high percentage shot it's
probably safer to do just bally that
ball but sometimes i think it's okay to
take some risk you know and be more
aggressive
go again that was a good one actually
come on bring that racket up a little
bit bring it up
anna bring the racket up a little higher
when you take it back okay
good love it
good whoa
love that one nice okay
it does it does it does yeah okay just
like a forehand
everything's the same except that you're
going to be making contact
higher which you do on the forehand as
well sometimes and you're taking it in
air but the tricky part is
in a real situation when you play points
you're
unlikely going to be stationary in this
area and when you recognize this high
ball and you have the courage to do a
swing volley
you'll probably have to do it in
transitions you have to move up from the
baseline
set your body get into a set position
and then hit it
so let's do that now okay i'm going to
have you go from the baseline up to this
area and then do a swing volley
okay so here's the key now so one thing
that
is super important when you want to do a
swing valley in transition is that
you have to be very very explosive and
get in that area kind of early
so that you then can wait for the ball
while it's dropping
in a set in a set position if you hit
this actually
truly on the run number one it's going
to probably drop too low
and you don't want to hit swing valleys
from the waist area
and it's very difficult to hit a ball
very hard while you're in transition
so super explosive when you see it and
then once you get there you
set up a little bit like this and then
you hit it like you wait for it to get
to the right height while you're already
there
i'll try it again come
here one more thing super important
just in general this is not the swing
valve this is any forehand that's hit in
transition
you don't want to run at the ball
straight on because then once you get
there you have to get
out of the way at the last millisecond
and you end up hitting it like this
so as you're running you leave the ball
to your side as you're running at it
because you're going to be hitting it on
the side you're not hitting here you're
hitting out here
space lateral spacing so the ball's
coming here's the ball
is the ball coming at you look it's
coming at you position yourself too
close
look it's gonna this way you're running
it like this go run forward
there you go you see yeah that's how you
have to
here you have to leave your body on the
left side of the ball
because you're hitting it on the right
don't don't ride the ball like this
you'll be too close
i'll try a few more go
go
fantastic go
fantastic job nice go
best one so far nice job
fantastic job nice very nice let me
teach you
what to do when you get a little bit
higher ball back there
so you don't do that two-handed thing
anymore
anna i don't i don't like
i don't like it at all but it gets into
the course
don't do that but the reason why they're
laughing
it's a shot that'll make a lot of sense
because
you know why the reason why you don't do
do anything with two hands up here
because it
reduces the range of motion and you
can't get any cartwheeling action going
so because on the overhead look
you got this right here and then you
reverse this so with two hands you can't
get any of that
so you're just going like that so you
can't get any power
i mean you can get an okay amount of
power but it's not the trick is that it
flies up
high but they can't it's not comparable
with uh
with a regular type overheads now it's
possible that you're probably better
at this than this at this moment it's
quite possible that's why you like doing
it
but i want you to stop right now okay no
more or that
i cannot accept this shot from any of my
students
just to generally when you get a ball
coming from the other side and you're
hitting an overhead in this area
the ball is very likely going out think
about it here put your racket up
say it again put your racket up all the
way down well i'm going to explain it to
you when you put your racket up
all right so put your racket up like
this so now if you're hitting an
overhead from here
the ball the ball is probably here okay
so this ball is very likely going
out so you shouldn't try to hit an
overhead
on the fly from back here it's probably
going out anyway so overhead can be
hit from here but it's going to bounce
first okay it's usually done on a
on a moon ball like this watch if
somebody hits it like this
you don't really want to do a swing
valley day just let it bounce and then
and then you hit an overhead that makes
sense yeah all right let me see it
a couple of things anna that you're
doing
wrong on the overhead in general not
just the bouncing overhead just the
overhead in general
you're waiting like this and then once
you're ready to hit you have to
take the racquet up and you have to do
everything at once so on the overhead
there is no backswing like you have on
the server remember on the server you
have the lag
none of that on the overhead you just
put the racket here like this
wait like this in the trophy phase now
at the same time
the left hand is going to be up because
you want to have the tilt and the
shoulders yes
so i what i do with the kids i always
tell them to point at the ball or
whatever works to keep your left hand up
so this is how you're going to be
waiting
you're also going to be turned sideways
that's how you're going to be set up
and then the timing on the overhead is
crucial because
you have to wait in this position for a
long time you have to set the ball up
perfectly
and then when it's very close when it's
already past the net when it's close to
you
that's when you start initiating the
overhead and hit it
and you accelerate like you said you
will accelerate towards the left pocket
down let me see a couple here i'm going
to hand feed it from sideways
okay there you go get your left hand up
left hand up
ready you're going to accelerate now
look at that good yes yes please
no you don't you don't need that don't
con cactus keep the wrist loose
keep the wrist loose yeah don't force
anything on the wrist keep it natural
not tilted
no keep the wrist natural like i don't
want you thinking about
uh yeah keep the wrist natural back here
watch i actually like ben
i actually like the wrist bent a little
bit naturally it's going to start moving
this way so you i like it bent a little
bit this way
so straight straight straight or even
bent down it's okay bent down
yeah it's fine left hand left hand up
hit do it again left hand up
you can bend the brace don't have to
it bend it down down a little bit
there you go
not bad and accelerate fast this way
there you go there you go
beautiful overhead now do it off the
bounce same thing
not bad but i like the racket down here
put it higher up
there you go set
set set up set up anna the movement is
key you got to move your feet
find the ball move your feet okay
not bad
okay that was a little better
best one so far okay come on up now
let's do an overhead that's
even more difficult where you're backing
up okay so i want you to touch the net
i'm gonna feed a ball like over your
head you're gonna have to back up in a
sideways position
so it's still gonna be the same setup as
before you're back up in a sideways
position
and then you're gonna hit the overhead
off your back leg okay
so it's okay to feel the pressure on
your back leg as you hit this one
and then you're going to land on the
front leg like this you show me a couple
times just
without the ball the movement yeah hi
ball it's behind me i'm about to go back
i have to go back and go
like that yeah it's a very difficult
shot
back it's a very difficult shot it's
actually an advanced shot but i want you
to try
i'm afraid of the camera no it's going
to be right around here because you're
going to start the net
good job and again go
it's all right go
nice not bad anna come again a couple
more
okay here if you go like this you won't
be able to drop the racket
you just go this way this way right here
good come again one more blasted
fantastic job wow